Don Alonzo Sanford Papers 1812-1983 1870-1915
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
- Series II: Diaries/Ledgers 1850-1919 (bulk 1880-1915)
  - Oversize ledgers—miscellaneous accounts, 1900-1914 (Box 30)
  - Oversize ledgers—miscellaneous accounts, 1907-1912 (Box 31)
  - Oversize ledgers—miscellaneous accounts, 1908-1912 (Box 32)
  - Oversize ledgers—properties, 1904-1905 (Box 33)
  - Oversize ledgers—rental accounts, 1898-1907 (Box 34)
  - Oversize ledgers—rental accounts, 1907-1913 (Box 35)
  - Photographic ledger—exposures, settings and subjects, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Transcribed diary/”Book of Knowledge”, 1876 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Trip logs, 1913-1914 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Undated (writings about Tucson, Indian issues) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Series III: Ranch Records, 1870- 1946 (bulk 1875-1910)
  This series contains varied records and correspondence related to Sanford’s large cattle/sheep ranch in the Sonoita Valley near Patagonia, Arizona. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Accounts and statements of trustees, 1903-1922 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Camp Huachuca and Fort Lowell—U.S. Army beef and barley contracts, 1878-1890 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Cattle brands, earmarks and vents, 1882-1912 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—A, 1885, 1896 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—Acuña, Casimiro, 1885-1886 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Andrade, Jose, 1876 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—Ashburn, O.F., 1885 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence—Atkinson, G.W., 1895, 1897 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence—B, 1879-1912 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence—Bayless, William H., 1884 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence—Bloxton, Robert V., 1881-1892 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence—Bloxton, Robert V., 1893-1894 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Bloxton, Robert V., 1895-1899 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—Borden, Selleck and Co., 1881 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—C, 1880-1912 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence—Cady, John, 1885-1895 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence—Cady, John, 1895 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Cady, John, 1896-1917 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Cameron, Colin, 1883-1889 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—Cameron, Colin, 1889-1890 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—Cameron, Colin, 1891 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Cameron, Colin, 1891-1912 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—Canetz, A., 1894-1896 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence—Chisholm, Alex, 1891-1899 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence—Christy and Wise Wool Commission Merchants, 1884-1888 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Coyot, Jack, 1892 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—D, 1881-1912 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—Dailey, Charles E., 1881-1895 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence—E, 1876-1892 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence—Elias, Concepcion, 1881 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Elkins, Benj, 1886-1888 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Elkins, Benj, 1888-1889 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—Etz, H.W., 1912 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—F, 1880-1881 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Fairbanks and Co., 1881 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—Farrell, Richard, 1897 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence—Ferrell, Lloyd and George, 1891-1897 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence—Franklin, Selim, 1913 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence—Fuller, Henry, 1897-1898 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence—F, 1881-1912 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence—Gatlin, A.A., 1912-1917 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence—Green, George, 1884-1885 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence—H, 1880-1912 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence—Hall, J.G., 1911 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence—Hammond, T.D., 1885 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence—Hazzard, S.E., 1897 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence—Hoag, H.W., 1882 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence—Hooker, H.C., 1885 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence—Humprey, I.M., 1897, 1891 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence—J, 1885, 1888 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Justice, Bateman and Co. Wool Merchants, 1882-1886 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence—K, 1885, 1890 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence—Kansas ranch, 1891-1897 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence—Kansas ranch and real estate, 1891-1893 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence—L, 1885-1912 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence—Lawrence, F.A., 1889-1890 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence—Lawrence, F.A., 1890 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Lawrence, F.A., 1891 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—Lawrence, F.A., 1891-1894 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—Leatherwood, R.N., 1884-1885 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence—Lord and Williams, 1880-1881 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence—M, 1882-1912 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Maish and Driscoll, 1895-1897 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Maloney, Mart, 1889-1892 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—McCleary, William, 1892 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—McKinley, S. and D., 1881-1882 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Meongua, Nacolete, 1893 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—Mitchell, A.J., 1892 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence—Mongo, Cleto, 1893 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence—Moore, R.M., 1881 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence—N, 1882, 1897 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence—New Mexico and Arizona Railroad Co., 1882-1892 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence—New Mexico and Arizona Railroad Co., 1894-1897 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence—New Mexico and Arizona Railroad Co., 1898-1900 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence—Newey, Bock, 1893 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence—North, O., 1892 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence—O, 1895-1897 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence—P, 1883-1893 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence—Pavey, Marion, 1892-1894 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence—Proctor, F.L., 1894 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence—Q, 1896-1897 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence—R, 1880-1911 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence—railroad companies, 1881-1912 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence—Richardson, R.R., 1882-1900 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence—Riggs, Harry B., 1903-1906 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Riggs, Harry B., 1907-1946 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—S, 1882-1912 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—Samaniego, M.G., 1890 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence—Sanders, W.L., 1885 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence—Sanford, Don Alonzo, 1880-1892 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Sanford, Don Alonzo, 1892-1916 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Sanford McKee, Amo, 1909-1912 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—sheepherding, 1880-1888 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—Smith, Horacio, 1896 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Steinfeld, Albert, 1911 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—Stuart, W.Dean, 1896, 1897 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence—Sue, Ah, 1895-1896 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence—T, 1880-1912 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence—Town, Isaac N., 1888 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence—Turner, T.J., 1890-1894 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence—unidentified, 1892, undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence—V, 1887 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence—Vail, Walter, 1880-1894 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence—Vaughan, J.U., 1892 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence—Vaughan, W.T., 1896 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence—Veck, W.S., 1883 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence—Vernon, F.M., 1889-1895 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence—Vickers, J.V., 1899-1899 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence—W, 1881-1912 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Wise, Morgan R., 1889-1892 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—Wise, Morgan R., 1893-1899 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—Wise, Joe, 1891-1892 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence—Wise, Joe, 1893-1897 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Expenses ledger, 1922-1925 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Expenses ledger, 1925 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Grazing permit application, 1912 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Horses, 1876-1911 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Income ledger, 1923-1925 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Inventories, 1883-1924 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Land grants/ pre-emption claims, 1875-1892 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Land leases, 1894-1912 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Land survey, 1886 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Legal agreements and contracts, 1881-1911 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Livestock, 1877-1916 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Mexico—correspondence and documents, 1881-1896 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous lists and notes, 1883-1911 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Receipts (Nogales and Tucson), 1876-1913 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—notes about estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—notes about San Jose de Sonoita land grant, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—notes about land grants and patents, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Sheepherding accounts, 1883-1885 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Stock book, 1897-1903 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Texas—cattle-- bills of sale, marks and brands, 1870-1873 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Trust statement, 1903-1908 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - U.S. government booklet on homesteading and public land, 1909, 1921 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Vaqueros / ranch hands, 1879-1897 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Vaqueros / ranch hands—ledger book, 1909-1911 (Box 42, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Property Records, 1878-1956 (bulk 1880-1915)
  This series contains records of properties owned by Don A. Sanford, both in Arizona and in Washington, D.C. The extensive rental holdings, including the Arizona Hotel (310 C Street Northwest) and the Rochester Hotel/Hotel Patience (910 E. Street N.W.), are detailed in documents including ledgers, income statements, repair specifications, receipts for building supplies and repair work. In addition, deeds and patents on Sanford’s territorial Arizona ranch lands and Tucson properties are included in this series. Mining related materials are also found in this series. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Arizona Hotel (Washington, D.C.), 1899-1910 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Hotel (Washington, D.C.), 1912-1917 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Hotel (Washington, D.C.), accounts, 1908 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Building permit correspondence (Washington, D.C.), 1898-1902 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Building /repair permit applications and correspondence, 1882-1901 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Building repairs dispute (Washington, D.C), 1899 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Forrest, C.M.—rental property management, 1901-1903 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Garber, B.S.—rental property management, 1905-1912 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—Ice House block (Tucson), 1884-1885 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—lease/sale of ranch property (Arizona), 1915-1926 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—mining (Arizona), 1881-1913 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1916-1920 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1917-1930 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1930-1936 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1937-1950 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Don Alonzo Sanford, 1950-1956 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence regarding estate of Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1923-1924 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence—Sanford Miller, Bertha and C.L. Sanford, 1925 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—Tucson property survey, 1888-1900 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Deeds (Tucson), 1878-1884 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Deeds (Tucson), 1885-1897 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Deeds (Washington, D.C.), 1893, 1902 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Deeds (Virginia), 1903 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Deeds and patents (Arizona), 1879-1888 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Deeds and patents (Arizona), 1886-1897 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Deeds and patents (Arizona), 1886-1897 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Deeds and patents (Arizona), 1903-1925 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Deeds of mining claims (Arizona), 1880 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Hotel Patience/ Rochester Hotel (Washington, D.C.), 1902-1904 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Insurance policies, 1882-1924 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Lease—Calabasas schoolhouse, 1887-1895 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Lease—Office of U.S. Surveyor General (Tucson), 1880-1884 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Mining location notices (Arizona), 1880-1885 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes and lists, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Proposal to construct road through property (Tucson), 1908-1909 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Real estate inspection reports (Washington, D.C.), 1915 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Real estate ledger, circa 1900 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Real estate titles/documents—912 E. Street N.W. (Washington, D.C.), 1902-1908 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Real estate transactions, 1890-1919 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental properties (Tucson), 1883-1919 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental properties (Washington, D.C.), 1888-1899 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C.), 1900-1910 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C.), 1911 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C.), January-May 1912 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C), June-December 1912 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C.), 1913 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Receipts for repairs on rental property (Washington, D.C.), 1914-1919 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Receipts, various (Washington, D.C.), 1878-1906 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, various (Washington, D.C.), 1907-1916 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Rental account statements, 1899-1915 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Rental agreements/leases (Tucson), 1882-1894 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Rental agreements/leases (Washington, D.C.), 1895-1909 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Rental agreements/leases (Washington, D.C.), 1908-1914 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Rental income statements (Tucson), 1916 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Rental inventories/lists, circa 1911-1915 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Rental property ledger pages (Washington, D.C.), 1915-1924 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Rental property ledger pages, circa 1897-1910 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Rental/property correspondence, 1882-1910 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Rental/property correspondence, 1911-1920 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Rental properties—inventories and lists, 1890-1901 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Rental receipts, 1915-1917 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Rental tenants, 1882-1910 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Repair agreements and contracts (Washington, D.C.), 1891-1906 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Repair estimates (Washington, D.C.), 1894-1911 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Repair ledger (Washington, D.C.), 1899 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Repair specifications (Washington, D.C.), 1895-1899 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Repair specifications (Washington, D.C.), 1900, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Repairs and property maintenance notes (Tucson), 1887-1913 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Repairs and property maintenance notes (Washington, D.C.), 1893-1910 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Repairs—Sanford residence (Washington, D.C.), undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Room rentals (Washington, D.C.), 1912-1913 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Street repairs (Tucson), 1925-1926 (Box 49, Folder 12)
- Series V: Legal Records, 1872-1959 (bulk 1872-1920)
  This series contains legal briefs, documents and research materials related to Sanford vs. Ainsa case regarding the San Jose de Sonoita land grant and which was argued before the U.S. Supreme Court in 1912. Also included are the “Indian Depredations” claims of D.A. and D.G. Sanford from 1872 and related material. In addition, materials regarding conflict with the City of Tucson over “the Wedge” building on Congress Street are present (Louisa and Don Sanford vs. The City of Tucson), as well as a number of other Arizona legal cases related to Sanford’s ranch in Patagonia. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Argument and briefs—Ainsa vs. N.M. and A.R.R. Co. (New Mexico and Arizona Railroad Company) and D.A. Sanford, 1893-1895 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Briefs—Etta Sanford, et al. vs. Santiago Ainsa, Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Briefs—Etta Sanford, et al. vs. Santiago Ainsa, Supreme Court of the United States, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Briefs— Frank Ely vs. N.M. and A.R.R. Co.(New Mexico and Arizona Railroad Company), et al., 1888 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Briefs—R.R. Richardson, Robert Bloxton, D.A. Sanford, et. al. vs. Santiago Ainsa, Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona, Supreme Court of the United States, 1907-1910 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Briefs—Territory of Arizona vs. Real Estate and Persons in the Delinquent List of the County of Pima for 1892 and D.A. Sanford, Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Briefs—various cases related to San Jose de Sonoita land grant and the Baca Float (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Briefs—William Faxon, Jr. vs. United States and George W. Atkinson, et al., Supreme Court of the United States, 1897 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - City of Tucson vs. Don A. Sanford, District Court, County of Pima, Territory of Arizona, 1886 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--Sanford vs. Ainsa (regarding San Jose de Sonoita land grant), 1886-1919 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence—Sanford vs. Ainsa, 1900-1913 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence—Sanford vs. Ainsa—McKee, Fred, 1903-1913 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence—Sanford vs. Ainsa—Rouse, Owen T. (attorney), 1902-1915 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence—various Tucson legal cases, 1886-1911 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and documents regarding the Baca Float, 1880-1934 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and documents regarding Sanford vs. Tully and Ochoa, 1881-1886 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and documents regarding water use/ Sanford ditch and dam, 1899-1913 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Documents relating to Sanford vs. Ainsa, 1890-1897 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Documents relating to Sanford vs. Ainsa, 1900-1913 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. C.P. Sykes and Mary E. Sykes, 1886 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. George Robinson, 1887 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. John Wood, Joseph Mills, Teodora Mills, 1886 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. M. Saldarte and H.W. Lowe, 1890 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. R.N. Leatherwood, et al., 1884 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Don A. Sanford vs. Tully and Ochoa, 1884-1895 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Denton G. Sanford, 1883-1888 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Don A. Sanford, 1915-1959 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Louisa Bloxton Sanford, 1921-1927 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Indian Depredations claim (Kiowas and Comanches) by D.G. and D.A. Sanford, U.S. Congress, 1872 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Indian Depredations claim (Kiowas and Comanches) by D.G. and D.A. Sanford, U.S. Congress, 1874-1888 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Indian Depredations claim (Kiowas and Comanches) by D.G. and D.A. Sanford, U.S. Congress, 1889-1895 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Indian Depredations Congressional Reports, 1877-1892 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - "Indian Depredations Laws and Opinions of the Court of Claims”, circa 1895 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Indian Depredations claim (Kiowas and Comanches) by D.G. and D.A. Sanford, U.S. Congress— transcribed materials, 1872 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Last will and testament of Don A. Sanford, 1915 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Legal fees and receipts, 1882-1903 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Louisa and Don A. Sanford vs. City of Tucson, 1902-1904 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Lowell vs. Sanford, 1886 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - McCrea vs. Bertha Sanford Miller, et al., 1928 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Power of attorney—Denton Sanford to Don Alonzo Sanford, 1864 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Power of attorney—Franklin Sanford to Don Alonzo Sanford, 1864 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Power of attorney—Louisa Bloxton Sanford to Don Alonzo Sanford, 1890 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Probate records— estate of Ana Maria Redonde de Aguerre, 1892 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - R.N. Leatherwood vs. Don A. Sanford, 1886 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Robert Bloxton vs. Theodore Stiles, Leo Goldschmidt and Albert Steinfeldt, 1887 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - S.M. Lowell vs. Denton G. Sanford, 1884 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Sanford family legal cases (Amo Sanford McKee vs. Bertha Sanford Miller; Bertha Sanford Miller vs. Amo Sanford McKee), 1924, undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Sanford vs. Robinson, 1887 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Transcript of Record, Supreme Court of the United States—Santiago Ainsa vs. The United States, 1894 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of Record, Supreme Court of the United States—Etta Sanford, et al. vs. Santiago Ainsa, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Court of Private Land Claims, 1886-1892 (Box 54, Folder 13)
- Series VI: Political Records, 1879-1894 (bulk 1880-1890)
  This series is comprised of various documents and correspondence related to Tucson and Arizona Territory politics during the 1880’s and 1890’s. Documents related to Sanford’s role as acting mayor of Tucson in 1884, in addition to his work as a Tucson city councilman, are present. Also included are Sanford’s writings about various political and civic matters. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Bill H.R. 3365, U.S. House of Representatives, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (incoming)—Tucson city government, 1884-1898 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (outgoing)—Tucson city government, 1883-1896 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding New York Times article, 1890 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Inventories and lists (Tucson), 1883-1885 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Proposals to city of Tucson, 1884, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Taxes—Tucson, circa 1885-1895 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Tucson city expenditures, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Tucson city governance, 1884-1890 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Tucson City Library, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Tucson mayoral election, 1888 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Tucson politics, 1885, undated (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Writings about Tucson and Arizona statehood, 1879-1890, undated (Box 55, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Financial Records, 1879-1955 (bulk 1880-1915)
  This series contains bank correspondence, checks, registers, financial statements, stocks and bonds. Also included are tax records and business receipts. The financial records herein are from Tucson, Nogales, Washington, D.C., Los Angeles and Wichita. Also present in this series are tax related documents, receipts and correspondence. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Accounts of Sanford and Hilton Miners and Railroad Market, Tucson, 1879-1883 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Automobile expenses, 1914-1916 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Bank book (Tucson), 1892 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Bank correspondence (Arizona), 1894-1910 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Bank correspondence (Arizona), 1911-1913 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Bank correspondence (Arizona), 1914-1916 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Bank correspondence (Arizona), 1917-1919 (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - Bank correspondence (Los Angeles), 1883 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Bank credit/debit statements (Tucson), 1909-1919 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Bank deposit slips (Tucson), 1882, 1903-1908 (Box 56, Folder 3)